（イタチ）性格は死ぬまで
変わらないが→
They say you take your personality
to the grave…
Well, I've already died once.
俺は一度　死んでいる。
そのつもりだ。
I intend to honor it.
The estranged brothers come
together to gang up on me?
（カブト）兄弟で
僕を仲間はずれですか…。
おもしろい。
How fun!
Sibling Tag Team
僕みたいなインテリは
じっと見つめられるのに→
Bookish types like me
aren't used to being stared at.
慣れてなくてね。
（サスケ）幻術対策か。
Countermeasures for genjutsu, huh?
Judging from their movements,
あの蛇たちの動き
俺たちを　ちゃんと感知してるぞ。
those snakes can sense
exactly what we're doing.
蛇は体温感知と
舌で匂いを口内に送り→
Snakes perceive their surroundings
through body heat
and smell through their tongues.
嗅覚感知もする。
You've studied a lot!
ずいぶん勉強したな。
まるで蛇博士だ。
You're like a snake expert now.
調べたさ。
大蛇丸を倒すためにな。
Of course I did. In order
to take down Orochimaru!
でも　ただの蛇博士じゃあ
この僕は倒せないよ。
However…
You can't beat me by just
being a snake expert.
ここは僕のフィールド。
This is my field.
Nature is on my side.
自然が僕の味方をする。
《んっ…　蛇が巨大化した？》
The snakes have gotten bigger!
地の利か？　トラップでもあると
みておけよ　サスケ。
Does this terrain give him
an advantage?
Be wary of traps, Sasuke.
トラップ？
Traps?
そんなものじゃないよ！
Oh, that's not what I meant!
それがスサノオだね。
That's the Susano'o, right?
手荒いぞ　サスケ。
Don't get too violent, Sasuke!
Remember, I told you
not to kill him!
殺すなというのは　わかってるな？
大蛇丸の力を
手に入れてるようだしな。
It seems he's acquired
Orochimaru's power.
そうそう死にはしねえよ！
He won't die so easily!
Sasuke!
サスケ！
フードだろ！
The hood!
What?!
何！？
Why that—!
この！
インテリも度がすぎてるな。
You're taking
the shyness thing too far.
顔の次は
姿まで隠して引きこもるか。
First, you hide your face,
and now your entire body?
脱皮して逃げてるだけか？
Did you just molt
to make a getaway?
大蛇丸の残り物を移植しただけの
劣化版だな。
All you have is what
you took from Orochimaru.
You're still nothing!
（カブト）サスケ君…
キミ　僕のことナメてるよね？
Sasuke… You underestimate me.
まあ　確かに僕のビンゴブックの
手配凶度は　キミ以下だったし→
Well, then again,
I was listed lower than you
on the danger scale
in the Bingo Book…
大蛇丸様に比べれば
たいしたことないしね。
And of course, I'm nothing
compared to Lord Orochimaru.
確かに。　それで隠れてるつもり
なんだとしたらな。
That's for sure.
Especially if you consider
this hiding.
（イタチ）サスケ　気をつけろ。
チャクラがあちこちにある。
Sasuke, watch out!
There's chakra everywhere…
どれが本物かは　わからんぞ。
It's hard to tell which
is the real one.
（カブト）流動的に
肉体変化する能力だよ。
It's the ability to transform
one's flesh into liquid.
体液を使って　分離する。
To detach and separate
using one's own life substance.
脱皮に見えるのはそのせいだね。
That's why it looks like a shedding.
これは　鬼灯一族の
肉体変化能力を調べ→
I've researched and applied
the Hozuki Clan's Flesh Transforming
ability to this technique.
応用し　生まれた技術だ。
You know him, don't you? Suigetsu.
キミも知ってるだろ？
水月だよ。
He can transform from human
to water, and back to human again.
彼は人から水へ
水から人へ変化する。
そして　かねてより
僕が持っている　圧倒的回復力。
Plus, I have the amazing ability
to recuperate quickly.
と言っても　これは
もともと　うずまき一族の→
I admit it's a healing technique
that I studied
女の体を調べて得た　回復技術。
from the body of a woman
originally from the Uzumaki Clan…
キミのよく知る　香燐だよ。
Someone you're quite familiar
with… Karin.
香燐が　うずまき一族だと！？
Karin's from the Uzumaki Clan?
（カブト）うずまき一族の血を継ぐ者は
髪が赤いのが特徴でね。
A special trait of those with
Uzumaki blood is their red hair.
生命力は　ゴキブリ並みだよ。
And their life force is
as tenacious as a cockroach's.
さあ　そうすると気になるのは
もう１人のキミのお仲間だけど。
Now then, you must be thinking
about the last member
of your team.
いや　もう仲間ではないのかな？
Or perhaps he's no longer
your comrade?
とにかく　あの３人を選んだキミは
お目が高いよ。
You have a discerning eye
since you chose those three.
この忍世界で　才能のない者は
存在すら否定されるけど→
In the Shinobi World,
those without talent are nothing.
才能がないならないで
あるところから奪い→
But those who lack talent
can just steal it from those who do.
己に付け足していけばいい。
どうやら重吾の能力も
持っているようだな。
Seems like you have
Jugo's ability too…
大蛇丸から呪印を食らってたか。
Did you receive a Curse Mark
from Orochimaru?!
（カブト）違う。
No!
あんなものは
ただの付け焼き刃さ。
That is just a temporary boost.
そのかたみは
己から体におさめた。
That memento is something
I actually cultivated myself…
龍地洞でね！
at Ryuchi Cave!
龍地洞だと！？　まさか…。
Ryuchi Cave?!
Impossible!
（カブト）そう　見つけたのさ。
Yes, I found it!
妙木山　湿骨林と並び伝えられる
伝承の　その場所を！
A place as legendary as Mt. Myoboku,
and the Shikkotsu Woods!
大蛇丸様だけじゃない。
Lord Orochimaru is not
the only one to have reached it.
この僕も行きつき→
I went there…
RYUCHI CAVE
白蛇仙人のもとで修業し
身につけた。
and trained under the guidance
of the White Snake Sage.
ついに　大蛇丸様を超えたんだよ。
And I was able to surpass
Lord Orochimaru at long last.
この僕が！
I did it!
サスケ！　焦るな！
Don't be impatient, Sasuke!
チッチッ。
この矢を　かわしただと！
He dodged…that arrow?
感知能力が
今までの比じゃなくてね。
My sensory ability is better
than it used to be.
自然エネルギーが
僕の味方をしてるのさ。
Nature Energy is my ally now.
自然エネルギー。
Nature Energy?
《やはり　こいつ…》
I knew it. So he does have…
（カブト）いいかい？
もともと重吾の一族は→
Listen…
The members of Jugo's clan
have always had
自然エネルギーを体内に取り込む
特別な体を持っていた。
special bodies that
absorbed Nature Energy.
それが　あの暴走の秘密さ。
急に強くなり荒々しくなる。
That's the secret behind
those rampages.
The ability causes them to suddenly
become more wild and powerful.
大蛇丸様は　重吾の暴走自体に
目をつけたんじゃなく→
Lord Orochimaru wasn't interested
in Jugo's rampages…
一族の力の由来に目をつけ
調べていたようだ。
so much as the origin
of his clan's power.
そして　ついに
その力の源を探り当てた。
And he finally found the source…
そこが龍地洞だったのさ。
It was Ryuchi Cave.
大蛇丸様は　すぐにも
その力を得ようと試みた。
Lord Orochimaru immediately
tried to acquire that power.
が　それに耐えうる体を
まだ持っていなかった。
But, he didn't yet possess a body
that could tolerate it.
だから…。
That's why…
この僕のように
完璧な仙人仕様には→
He couldn't become the perfect Sage…
まだ　なれなかったんだよ　彼も。
that I have become!
そうか　やはり　仙人モードの力を…。
I see… As expected…
you're using Sage Mode power.
大蛇丸と同じだ！
出来損ないの蛇が！
You're just like Orochimaru!
A disgusting snake!
蛇博士なら
わかってほしいなぁ。
You ought to know better,
you snake expert…
僕は　もう蛇ではない。
I'm no longer a snake.
完全な仙人の力は　蛇を脱皮し→
With my perfect Sage power,
I've shed my snakeskin…
龍へと昇華したんだよ！
I am now a dragon!
（マダラ）答えてみろ。
Answer me.
そいつらが　スサノオを使う
使わない　どちらだ？
Would you like these clones
to use Susano'o or not?
Your choice.
答えようもないか
お前らごときに。
The likes of you have no answer.
Well, I'll answer for you.
では　俺が答えてやろう。
（メイ）まさか！
（エー）おのれ～！
Impossible…
Damn him!
使うだ。
They will use it.
（綱手）こいつら。
１人　５体が相手か。
Damn them.
Each one of us must take on five.
Five to one…
（我愛羅）５対１…。
（オオノキ）いや　２５対５じゃぜよ。
No, it's 25 to five.
土影様…。
Lord Tsuchikage?
（オオノキ）互いをカバーし
互いに連携をとる。
We'll guard each other's backs
and coordinate attacks.
わしらは　五影じゃ！
We are the Five Kage!
おう！
そうだ！
いくぞ！
– Yes!
– That's right!
Let's go!
（いのいち）五影様たちが
マダラに苦戦している。
The Five Kage are struggling
against Madara.
（青）とんでもないチャクラだ。
There's unbelievable chakra!
（シカク）伝説の忍のうえに
穢土転生体だからな。
He's not just a legendary shinobi…
He's been reanimated.
不死　チャクラも無限ときている。
He's immortal,
so he has infinite chakra.
五影様たちといえども
苦戦は必至か。
It's no wonder the Five Kage
are having a hard time.
（マブイ）やはり　穢土転生の術者を
なんとかしなくては…。
We must do something about
the user of this Reanimation Jutsu.
捜索班からの連絡は？
Any word from the Investigative Unit?
Nothing. They've been searching
every spot thought to be a hideout.
何もない。　アジトらしき場所を
しらみつぶしに当たっているが→
カブトの痕跡すら
見つからないようだ。
And not one sign of Kabuto.
And the Sensory Unit?
（シカク）感知班は？
We're getting no response.
こちらには　なんの反応もない。
うまく結界を
張っているのかもしれん。
He's probably put up a barrier.
Shall I send out more shinobi?
増員を出しますか？
We've sent every man available.
出せるギリギリまで出した。
それ以上は　戦線に穴が開く。
Anymore will weaken the front.
（シカク）カブトに　これほど
してやられようとはな…。
Who would have imagined that
Kabuto could do so much?
Sage Art: White Extreme Attack!
仙法　白激の術！
ぐっ…。
《耳が…　それに
骨がきしむようだ》
My ears…
And my bones… They feel like
they're being grated.
《光と音で　視覚と聴覚を…。
It's a jutsu that uses
light and sound
to impair vision and hearing…
空気振動を起こして→
A jutsu that causes
the air to oscillate…
感覚を麻痺させ
動きを止める術…》
to paralyze the senses,
freezing movement.
《蛇の角膜で
視界を閉じて光を無視し→
A snake's cornea can
block out the light
and by turning my flesh
into fluid,
体内を液化して
音と振動に柔軟に耐える。
I can easily absorb
the sound and vibration.
The only one who can move
freely under these conditions…
この状況で動けるのは
仙人仕様の僕だけだ！》
is me in Sage Mode!
《くっ！　ダメだ…
スサノオを維持できない》
It's no use!
We can't maintain Susano'o!
Yes, I should go for Itachi.
《やはり　狙うはイタチ…。
頭の中の札を書き換えて
また駒にするか？
I'll rewrite the Paper Seal
in his head
and turn him into
my pawn again.
Or even better…
いや　それより》
Itachi…
イタチ　キミはどうやら→
It seems you always
end up finding me.
僕の居場所を
嗅ぎ当てるのが上手らしい。
Can you sense my chakra?
僕のチャクラを
感知できてるのかな？
でも　あれれ？
But…wait a minute…
I'm impressed you were able
to pass through my barrier,
((僕の結界を通り抜け
よく　ここがわかったね。
and find this place.
お前に操られている間
お前のチャクラが→
When you were controlling me,
I was able to pinpoint where
your chakra was coming from.
どこからきているかは
はっきり感じていた。
(これも　術のリスクだ))
That's another risk
of this jutsu.
キミは　お前に
操られている間って言ったはず。
I remember you said,
"when I was controlling you…"
なら今は　僕のチャクラは→
So you can't sense
my chakra now, can you?
感じ取れていないって
ことだよね。
また　お得意のウソで
僕を騙そうと？
You're trying to trick me
with your lies again?
I never said I was the one
お前のチャクラを感知できたのが
誰も俺だとは言ってない。
who was able to sense
your chakra.
それができたのは
一緒にいた長門だけだ。
Only Nagato could do that,
and I was with him.
俺にそんな力はない。
I have no such ability.
それに　今にしても→
Besides, even now, I know
what your target is anyway.
お前が　どこを狙うかは
はっきりしている。
I merely move to protect that which
I think you'll most want to attack.
なら　先にそこを守ればいい。
利を求め　慎重なお前が
サスケを欲しがってるなら→
If a man as cautious and
opportunistic as you wants Sasuke…
you will go for him first.
先に　サスケを捕らえる。
己の術が　分析されない
早いうちが→
Your best chance to
capture Sasuke is now,
before either of us figures
out your jutsu.
サスケ奪取の確率は高く→
そのあとも　俺を脅す持ち札として
サスケを利用できるからな。
And after that, you could use
Sasuke to manipulate me.
キミが　うちは一族のなかで
他と違うのは→
What sets you apart from
the rest of the Uchiha Clan
本当の意味での瞳力だ。
is that you have true Visual Prowess…
人の心を見透かし　心を読む。
You have the ability to peer into
and read people's souls.
And use what you learn in battle.
そして　それを戦いに利用する。
だからこそ　人を騙すのがうまい。
That is why you are so good
at deceiving people…
You died lying in the first place,
そもそも　キミは
ウソをつき通して死んだ→
that makes you a dirty lying ninja
through and through!
根っからの
ウソつき忍者だしね。
《チッ！　天井に！》
He's on the ceiling!
いくら２人だろうと
付け焼き刃のコンビじゃ→
You think a makeshift team of two
can outwit my perception skills?
僕の感知能力を
出し抜けやしないよ。
しかも　ウソつきな兄貴のせいで→
And because your brother
lied so much,
you know nothing about each other…
ずっと仲違いしていた
兄弟なんかじゃね…。
Sasuke…
サスケ。
Do you remember that time
昔　俺の任務についてきた
ときのことを覚えているか？
you tagged along with me
on my mission?
猪だ。
The wild boar?
((イタチ：いってきます。
I'm off.
(お前…))
You…?!
Oh that, I remember.
あれか…　思い出した。
猪？
Wild boar…?
((いってきます。
I'm off.
You…?!
お前…。
I heard you're going on
a wild boar hunt, Big Brother!
猪退治なんだってね　兄さん。
それも　オバケみたいに
でっかい猪なんだってね。
I heard it's big like a monster.
畑を荒らしまわる
悪いやつだから→
And it's bad, because
it's tearing up the fields.
兄さんが任務を受けて
やっつけにいくんでしょう？
Isn't that why you're going
on the mission, to take it down?
でも　兄さん１人なんだよね？
And you're going alone, right?
でも　大丈夫だよ。
僕が一緒に行くから。
兄さんだって知ってるよね？
僕の弓の腕前。
何度も　一緒に
獲物をとりに行ったから。
許せ　サスケ。　また今度だ。
え～！？　兄さん！
兄さ～ん！
ハァ　ハァ…。
よく追いついたな。
修業…　してるから…。
上がってこい。
うん。
あれだね。
殺すなよ。
(え？
痛めつければ山へ帰る))
いくぞ。
ああ。
((急所は　はずせ))
わかってる。
((今だ！))
俺の刀を奪って
尾の蛇を切って逃げる気だ！
だから焦るなって言ったのに。
そうだった　忘れてた。
ふだん　ここに
角なんてないもんだから　ついね。
((うわ～っ！
兄さん…。
思いっきり　はずしたな。
ごめん　兄さん。
まだまだ修業が足りないな。
帰るぞ　サスケ。
戻ったら　修業をつけてやる。
(うん！))
今なら　あの大猪も
仕留められそうだな。
大猪より　まずは
あの蛇を仕留めないとな。
ああ。
＜　きょうから１２代目＞
＜旬の野菜が大好きな豆助＞
豆助　きょうのお野菜は
今が旬のあれよ
＜　その野菜とは…＞